

(212) 810-0258 | New York, NY

E: davidjkirsch@gmail.com | G: github.com/David-Kirsch | L: linkedin.com/in/davidjkirsch | W: www.davidkirsch.dev

#### SUMMARY

Full stack web developer with a creative side and a passion to solve real world problems. Quick ability to learn and adapt to new technologies and thrives in both team and individual settings. Experienced in working under pressure in an agile, fast-paced environment and multitasking while maintaining accuracy and efficiency.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript, Ruby, Java, Swift, HTML, CSS

Frameworks: React, Ruby on Rails Databases: SQLite, PostgreSQL, MySQL

Version Control: Git

**Design:** Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Lightroom, Final Cut Pro X

### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

#### Rate My Landlord - GitHub (Backend, Frontend) | Demo | www.ratemyapartment.nyc

A community-based web application that gives a voice to tenants, giving potential tenants all the information they need to help make the decision that is right for them when selecting their next apartment.

- Built using ReactJS for Frontend and Ruby on Rails for Backend.
- Utilized a variety of APIs to grab building violations, safety ratings and verify uploaded photo content.

# Lingo Chat - Github| Demo | https://thawing-river-87320.herokuapp.com

A chat group web application that allows users to chat with anyone from around the world without worrying about the language barrier.

- Implemented Firebase (Cloud Firestore) as the database, allowing real-time updates in the chat rooms and ReactJS for Frontend
- Used Microsoft Translator API to allow users to communicate with people around the world.

#### G-Wiz - GitHub (Backend, Frontend) | Demo

A fun and interactive way to learn new words and test your understanding of related words. A great SAT prep, starting from elementary school level up to high school.

- Built with Ruby on Rails for the backend and Vanilla JS for frontend, along with Animate.css for animation.
- Collected test questions from an API to build the database using RESTful design

### PowerUp - GitHub | Demo

An educational game built for iOS that helps facilitate the breaking down of base10 number to binary (base2) in a fun and interactive way.

• Self-taught Swift and Xcode to be able to produce an iOS application

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Computer Programming Teacher | P.U.L.S.E. High School | Bronx, NY | August 2017 to January 2018

- Prepared various classroom activities and assessment methods to promote retention of study materials.
- Created lesson plans, course materials and homework assignments covering established coursework and textbook information.

### Tech Support | RFCUNY | Brooklyn, NY | May 2016 to July 2017

- Troubleshot and diagnosed problems to accurately resolve wide range of technical issues.
- Installed, modified and repaired software and hardware to resolve technical issues.

#### **Performer** | Various Locations | October 2008 to August 2014

- · Studied scripts, choreography, and music to be a great storyteller
- Attended auditions and dance classes regularly to maintain/ build skills

#### **EDUCATION**

Certificate of Completion: Full Stack Web Development

Flatiron School - NYC- Financial District

Bachelor of Technology: Software Development (Major GPA 3.3)

New York City College Of Technology Of The City University Of New York - Brooklyn, NY

American Musical And Dramatic Academy - New York, NY

January 2020

October 2006 - May 2007

October 2020